workforce.com 2017-07-31

# Privacy Policy | Human Capital Media

To opt out of some or all Human Capital Media emails please send your name, email address, and any additional information about the circumstance to help us best serve you to  **[opt-out@humancapitalmedia.com](mailto:opt-out@humancapitalmedia.com)**.

Human Capital Media, a division of MediaTec Publishing Inc. — publisher of _Chief Learning Officer_ magazine, _Talent Economy_ magazine and _Workforce_ magazine and operator of the leading online industry resource — understands the importance of protecting the privacy of its respected Web site users. The information collected is used to market and improve the services we offer, to improve the Web sites’ content and to contact you with updates to the Web sites, provide you with subscribed deliverables or for other marketing purposes.

Certain areas of Human Capital Media’s Web sites, including but not limited to subscriptions, forums, discussions, comments and pay areas, require registration or a passwords for access. Information obtained from registered users of these areas also may be used for Human Capital Media marketing purposes, and cookies may be used in those and other areas, as is described in this policy. Information obtained in these areas also may be used in accordance with agreements governing access to and use of the specific areas. In addition, visitors to Human Capital Media’s Web sites may choose to register for login user IDs and passwords to gain access to some interactive features on the Web sites. Log file data and other information gathered from registered users of Human Capital Media’s Web sites are used to improve customer experience. When attending our in-person events, participating in our customer-sponsored webcasts, using portions of our Web sites and signing up for elected services (e.g., free subscriptions), users must register first.

Human Capital Media provides some clients with customized, private-label, sponsored products and services. When we join with other parties to provide specific services or events (we do not share credit card information with such third parties), then we may share (provide and receive) information about our customers with such third parties, subject to the customers’ preferences (as described in the “Permission” section below). Information collected in connection with online webcasts/seminars, will be shared with the sponsor of the particular webcast(s)/seminar(s), subject to the given customers’ preferences (as described in the “Permission” section below). Human Capital Media is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of our third-party sites and sponsors. You should consult the privacy policies at those sites to determine how your information may be used.

### What information does Human Capital Media capture about visitors to its Web sites?

Human Capital Media’s Web server uses an extended log file format, which captures date and time of visit, referring address (location from which a visitor comes to one of Human Capital Media’s Web sites), type of Internet browser and visitor’s IP address. (Each computer that connects to the Internet is assigned a unique number, an IP address, for identification purposes). The log file does not capture a visitor’s e-mail address or passwords. For services that require payment (e.g., certain events, products and subscriptions), we also collect credit card information (e.g., account name, number and expiration date). We may collect unique identifiers (e.g., mother’s maiden name) that we disclose to the auditors strictly for industry standard reporting and audit verification purposes.

### **Does Human Capital Media ask for personal information?**

Several areas of Human Capital Media’s Web sites ask for personal information. In these areas, your name, address, e-mail address, billing information and business profile are requested. This information is collected to help us further develop our services, provide you access to valuable Human Capital Media Internet-based information and services, provide you with our printed magazines and publications and bill you for pay services if you elect to use them. We also may collect information about a user’s professional responsibilities (e.g., job title and purchasing responsibilities, company information and professional certification).

### **How does Human Capital Media use the information?**

The information collected through our Web sites helps us identify the type of Web site content our customers’ value most. We use this information to communicate with users and provide requested services, and for our Web site visitors, to provide a more personalized experience on our Web sites to market and improve our Web sites and services. We also use this information to send you e-mail notifications about updates to the Web sites and to contact you by other means for marketing and/or for industry reporting purposes. Our policy is to not give, sell or otherwise distribute the information collected through our sites to third parties outside of Human Capital Media (unless required by law); provided, however, in some cases we may use suppliers to assist us in collecting, using or otherwise processing, for our benefit, the information obtained through our Web sites (e.g., Independent auditors may need to certify the eligibility of service subscribers). Our practice is to require our suppliers to conduct such activities consistent with this policy and our requirements, subject to the given customer’s preferences (as described in the “Permission” section below). Contact information collected in connection with surveys and contests is used to notify the winners and award prizes, and to monitor or improve the use of and satisfaction with our Web sites or other Human Capital Media products or services. Information submitted through contact forms will be forwarded to the appropriate internal departments or vendors in reference.

### **Correction/Updating Personal Information**

If information you provide Human Capital Media changes, or if you no longer desire our product(s)/service(s), we provide a way to correct or update your personal data.

### **Communications From Human Capital Media**

In order to best serve our customers, we may send updates that contain important information about our products and services. We also may communicate with a customer to provide requested services and for account-related issues via e-mail, phone or postal mail. In addition to such service and product-essential messages, we offer our customers the option to receive information about our company, related products, services and special deals. Users, however, can choose not to receive these communications from us, as set forth in the “Permission” section below.

To opt out of some or all Human Capital Media emails please send your name, email address, and any additional information about the circumstance to help us best serve you to  **[opt-out@humancapitalmedia.com](mailto:opt-out@humancapitalmedia.com)**.

### **Permission**

Human Capital Media customers are given the opportunity to choose whether to receive information from us and our affiliates that is not directly related to the product or service for which they registered (or which they otherwise agreed to receive). Customers have the opportunity to choose whether to have personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes. Customers can change their preferences at any time. Please note that we have a number of brands and products. You may choose to opt out of certain brands and products selectively or for all our lists. Your choice to resubmit your e-mail address and contact details to us also will reset your privacy preferences. In addition, for those customers who are California residents, you may have additional rights, as described in the “Your California Privacy Rights” section below.

Please note that we will endeavor to implement your permission requests within a reasonable time, although for a time you may continue to receive mailings, etc., transmitted based on information released prior to the implementation of your request. In addition, please note that even after such request is implemented, you will continue to receive information directly related to the product or service for which you registered (or which you otherwise agreed to receive), so you always are kept informed.

### **What happens when I leave a Human Capital Media Web site to visit a Human Capital Media media-linked Web site?**

Parts of Human Capital Media’s Web sites consist of products and services hosted by third-party businesses. When you leave a Human Capital Media Web site to visit one of these sites, the only information transferred to the third party is the fact that you came from a Human Capital Media’s Web site (the referring address). This practice allows the third party to monitor its own Web site traffic, but does not provide them with any information about you. Human Capital Media is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of our third-party sites and sponsors. You should consult the privacy policies at those sites to determine how your information may be used.

### **E-Mail Newsletters**

Some users may subscribe to our e-mail newsletters. During this process, we ask for contact information (e.g., name, e-mail address, phone number) and information about the subscriber’s professional interests and responsibilities. Recipients of our newsletters can unsubscribe using the instructions listed at the end of the e-mail newsletter.

To opt out of some or all Human Capital Media emails please send your name, email address, and any additional information about the circumstance to help us best serve you to  **[opt-out@humancapitalmedia.com](mailto:opt-out@humancapitalmedia.com)**.

### **Surveys and Contests**

Periodically, we invite Human Capital Media’s Web site users and other customers to provide information via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary, and the Web site user or other customer therefore has a choice whether to disclose requested contact information (e.g., name and mailing address) and demographic information (e.g., zip code or job title).

### **Interactive Features**

Human Capital Media’s Web sites offer interactive and community features (e.g., discussion boards, webcasts and user profiles). Note that all personal information provided via such features becomes public information for which we are not responsible.

### **What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a series of data characters that, when programmed into a Web site, is placed by the Web server into the browser’s application folder on your computer. Once placed onto your machine, the cookie will allow the Web site to “recognize” you as a unique individual.

### **Does Human Capital Media use cookies?**

Cookies are used to achieve two goals. The first is to provide Human Capital Media with the capability to personalize information for certain segments of our customer base. Secondly, in some instances, cookies are used to allow Human Capital Media the opportunity to associate individual customers with their information profiles. For example, through the use of cookies, CLOmedia.com log-in can “remember” your user ID when you log in at CLOmedia.com on your computer.

In addition, some of our business affiliates use cookies on our Web sites and e-mail newsletters, in ads or promotions. Human Capital Media is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of our third-party sites and sponsors. You should consult the privacy policies at those sites to determine how your information may be used.

### **Can cookies be removed from my hard drive?**

Yes, cookies can be removed from your hard drive. Also, depending on what type of Web browser and what browser version you are using, you may be able to change the properties on your cookie file so that cookies are not used or saved. Please check with your browser provider for more information on removing cookies. If users reject Human Capital Media’s Web sites’ cookies, they may be limited in the use of some areas of Human Capital Media’s Web sites (e.g., a user may not be able to participate in sweepstakes, contests or drawings, forums, discussions, etc.)

### **What is a Web beacon?**

Also called a “Web bug”, a “pixel tag” or a “clear GIF,” used in combination with cookies, a Web beacon is an often-transparent graphic image, usually no larger than 1 pixel x 1 pixel, that is placed on a Web site or in an e-mail and is used to monitor the behavior of the user visiting the Web site or sending the e-mail. When the HTML code for the Web beacon points to a site to retrieve the image, at the same time, it can pass along information such as the IP address of the computer that retrieved the image, the time the Web beacon was viewed and for how long, the type of browser that retrieved the image and previously set cookie values. All data available through the use of Web beacons is in most cases already gathered by the serving Web server’s log files.

### **Does Human Capital Media use Web beacons?**

Human Capital Media employs the use of Web beacons to track user visits to all Human Capital Media online content. The use of Web beacons enables us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on Human Capital Media sites and via our e-mail newsletters.

In addition, we use Web beacons, provided by our ad-serving partner, to help manage our online advertising for Human Capital Media products and services. These Web beacons enable our ad server to recognize a browser’s cookie when a browser visits these sites and to learn which banner ads bring users to our Web sites. The information used in this process is not personally identifiable.

### **Third-Party Cookies**

Human Capital Media uses third-party advertising technology to serve ads for our products and services. This technology uses non-personal information about your visits to these Human Capital Media Web sites to serve advertisements to you. In the course of this service, a unique third-party cookie may be sent to your browser.

### **Links**

Human Capital Media Web sites contain links to other sites. Human Capital Media is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of our third-party sites and sponsors. You should consult the privacy policies at those sites to determine how your information may be used.

### **Security**

Human Capital Media uses industry-standard technology to protect information about our customers stored on our servers and in transit to our vendors for processing on our behalf. Sensitive information that is transmitted to us online (e.g., credit card number) is encrypted and transmitted securely. Access to ALL stored customer information is restricted based on administrative permissions. Employees of Human Capital Media and our service providers who need information to perform specific tasks (e.g., fulfilling a magazine subscription) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Human Capital Media servers that house personally identifiable information are kept in a state-of-the-art secure facility.

### **Additional Resources on Information Privacy**

The Electronic Privacy Information Center focuses public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure. EPIC Alert is the online newsletter of the Electronic Privacy Information Center in Washington, D.C. The newsletter is bi-weekly and covers issues related to privacy and civil liberties in the information age.

### **California Privacy Rights**

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits those customers who are California residents to request that Human Capital Media not share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing use.

To make such a request, write us at:

Human Capital Media  
111 E. WACKER DRIVE  
STE. 1200  
CHICAGO, IL 60601

Human Capital Media reserves the right to amend the Privacy Policy at any time with or without notice. Please check back frequently in the event of changes.

Your use of any Human Capital Media Web site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy.
